

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

### **Modularized Software Curriculum**

Restructured a software development program into a decoupled course heirarchy, boosting sales 10% by offering more affordable options.

#### **Optimized React Course**

Spearheaded the refactoring of a React course that led to a 25% increase in student project completion

# **Enhanced Social Media Content**

Produced educational and testimonial video content for social media, improving impressions by 30%.

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript	****
Python	****
C#	****
TypeScript	****
SQL	****
Java	***

React	****
Django	****
Flask	<b>★★★★</b> ☆
ASP.NET	****
Next.js	****

# **DevOps**

Docker	***
Jenkins	<b>★★★☆</b> ☆
AWS	<b>★★★☆</b> ☆
GCP	<b>★★★☆☆</b>
Kubernetes	***

# **PROJECTS**

A tour management web app for independent bands and artists, built with Next is. Diango and SQL, and deployed on GCP via Docker and Jenkins.

## **Portfolio**

My professional portfolio, featuring a chatbot clone of me via the openai API. Built with Next.js and tailwind, it leverages puppeteer to generate a PDF of my CV from raw data.

### Genevieve Heyward

An artist site built with Squarespace supplemented with some of my JavaScript widgets.

# Dan O Stoffels

# Full Stack Developer | React Specialist | Django Specialist

dan.stoffels@gmail.com Portfolio GitHub



#### **SUMMARY**

With over 12 years of experience ranging from web development to full stack engineering, I specialize in React and Diango. I have instructed over 1000 students in the fields of audio and software engineering during my 8 years in higher education. My passion for music, technology and teaching brings a structured and creative approach that results in innovative solutions.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Instructor of Software Development**

**1** 04/2022 - 02/2024 Milwaukee, WI (remote)

# devCodeCamp

- Outlined and initiated the restructuring of a monolithic full-stack course into a focused, modular course hierarchy, resulting in a 10% increase to enrollments through wider variety and affordability.
- ♦ Designed a comprehensive React course that introduces students to full-stack React through 8 lectures, a 25video tutorial series and 6 projects, improving student outcomes by 25%.
- ♦ Collaborated on the development of a C#/ASP.NET curriculum aimed at boosting student comprehension of OOP principles, data structures, MVC patterns and REST APIs.
- Wrote and produced educational shorts, showcasing "pro tips" on best practices and improving worflows, that resulted in a 30% increase in engagement on LinkedIn and TikTok.
- Trained over 300 students in full-stack software development and DevOps with tech stacks such as MERN, Django, Flask, ASP.NET, Spring, MySQL, Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes and AWS.

### Stage Manager and Monitor Engineer

**11/2017 - 02/2022** 

Nashville, TN

#### LANCO Music (Band)

- 4 Worked directly with artist and tour management to organize support for A-list touring acts such as Luke Combs, Dierks Bentley, Miranda Lambert and Brothers Osborne.
- 4 Designed, built and operated a redundant backing track system and its MIDI control network, improving stage operations and preventing dropouts during performances.
- 4 Managed stage and monitors for over 400 shows internationally, ranging from mid-sized clubs to A-list arena tours, fairs and large festivals including Stagecoach and C2C.

# Freelance Artist Production and Management

11/2011 - present

Madison, WI

# Self Employment

- Co-created and produced 31 episodes of "Crusty Adventures" with Brett Newski, a travel mockumentary series showcasing life as a touring musician mixed with skits and misadventures.
- ♦ Volunteered as a technical director for the Steel Bridge Songfest from 2007-2021, managing live and studio production for over 200 artists, including Pat MacDonald and Jackson Browne, during three separate weeklong songwriting events annually.
- 4 Web development and content management for music artists such as Geri X, Genevieve Heyward and Brett Newski, focused on web traffic and social media impressions that resulted in increased merch and ticket sales.

# Instructor of Audio Engineering

**1** 01/2010 - 05/2015

#### Madison Media Institute

- ♦ Initiated, developed and administered curriculum for two live sound courses, resulting in an 18% increase in placement and brought greater community engagement by providing PA systems and students to local events.
- 4 Booked local and national bands for 8-hour studio recording classes and supervised their production in 3 separate studios, expanding the network and visibility of the school.
- ♦ Graduated more than 700 students in audio engineering, with training in live sound, studio production and Pro Tools expert level certification.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Certificate in Full Stack Software Development

devCodeCamp

**11/2021 - 04/2022** 

**1** 01/2013 - 07/2014

Madison, WI

Milwaukee, WI

**1** 01/2006 - 04/2007

Madison, WI

# Madison Media Institute

Bachelor of Science in Entertainment and Media Business

Associate of Arts in Recording and Music Technology

Madison Media Institute